Guide to the William Benton Papers 1839-1973
University of Chicago Library
- Series VII: Addenda
  - Subseries 4: Career
    - Miscellaneous - "China Goes to School" - Unidentified typescript that appears to be an updated manuscript of Warren Preece manuscript "Education in China" found in Box 538, circa 1960s (Box 750, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous - George Kennan - "Diary of Cruise Aboard 'M/V ARVI' June 21-July 15, 1971 - With letter to William Benton, 1971 (Box 750, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 5: Audiovisual
    - Photograph - Helen Hemingway (Benton) as bridesmaid, undated (Box 751, Folder 1)
    - Photographs - Wililiam and Helen Benton and children, undated (Box 751, Folder 2)
    - Photograph - Willliam Benton, undated (Box 751, Folder 3)
    - Photograph - Helen Hemingway (Benton) - Connecticut College Graduation Picture, 1922 (Box 751, Folder 4)
    - Photographs - William Benton - Seven photos of Benton at the University of Chicago - With ephemera, 1944 (Box 751, Folder 5)
    - Photograph - Benton family - "In Vice President Barkley's Office, July 6, 1950" - With ephemera, 1950, Includes a letter from William Bention to his son, Charles Benton from August 2, 1950. (Box 751, Folder 6)
    - Photographs - Democratic National Convention - With ephemera, 1952, Typed caption: "Photographs taken from the television screen at the Democratic National Convention in Chicago in the summer of 1952. (Sent to Senator Benton by Mr. Joseph Fisch of the Harvard Law School Forum shortly after Senator Benton addressed the Forum in February 1955.) (Box 751, Folder 7)
    - Photograph - Benton family - Visiting President Tito on Brioni, 1953 (Box 751, Folder 8)
    - Photograph - Governor Stevenson and family visiting the Benton family - Eze-Sur-Mer, August 5-19, 1953 (Box 751, Folder 9)
    - Photograph - William, Helen and John Benton in Moscow - November 7, 1955 - With ephemera, 1955, Includes a typed press reslease about the visit and the photograph. (Box 751, Folder 10)
    - Photograph - Hubert H. and Muriel Humphrey - With inscription to Helen and William Benton and ephemera, 1958, Includes autograph letter from Hubert H. Humphrey to Helen Benton. (Box 751, Folder 11)
    - Photographs - William and Helen Benton with Adlai Stevenson - Bullfight in Valencia, Spain, July, 1959 (Box 751, Folder 12)
    - Photograph - William and Helen Benton with Adlai Stevenson and others on the "Flying Clipper," 1959 (Box 751, Folder 13)
    - Photographs - William Benton and Adlai Stevenson - Trip to Latin America, late 1950s (Box 751, Folder 14)
    - Photograph - William Benton, circa 1960 (Box 751, Folder 15)
    - Photograph - William Benton with Ambassador Blair and Mary Lasker - With caption and ephemera, 1961 (Box 751, Folder 16)
    - Photograph - UNESCO House, Paris - William Benton, 1963 (Box 751, Folder 17)
    - Photographs - Soviet writers visiting the Benton estate in Southport, CT - With ephemera, 1964, Includes correspondence with Tamara Mamedova and newspaper articles, from Thanksgiving 1964. (Box 751, Folder 18)
    - Photograph - William Benton receiving the first William Benton Medal from the University of Chicago and University President George Beadle - With ephemera and caption, 1968 (Box 751, Folder 19)
    - Photograph - William Benton and Marjorie Craig Benton, circa late 1960s-1970s (Box 751, Folder 20)
    - Photograph - Catharine McKeown Small, circa 1920s (Box 751, Folder 21)
    - Audio cassette tape - "Senator Benton's Speech, National Sales Meeting, 10/1/1961" - Encyclopaedia Britannica - Three copies, undated, Three copies; one copy says Part 1 - 36:49, Part 2 - 25:03. (Box 751, Folder 22)
    - Audio cassette tape - "How to Think about Mortimer" - Dr. Mortimer J. Adler's 80th Birthday Celebration - December 18, 1982, undated (Box 751, Folder 23)
    - Photograph - Grace and Tom Dodd - With Inscription to Helen and William Benton, undated (Box 752, Folder 1)
    - Photograph - Hubert and Muriel Humphrey - With inscription to Helen and William Benton, undated (Box 752, Folder 2)
    - Photograph - Man - Taken by Florence Homalka - With inscription from unidentified person on ephemera, undated (Box 752, Folder 3)
    - Photograph - U.S. Capitol Building - With ephemera, undated (Box 752, Folder 4)
    - Photograph - Benton family in Vice President Alben Barkley's Office - With caption, circa 1950 (Box 752, Folder 5)
    - Photograph - William Benton and Adlai Stevenson - Latin American Trip - Taken by Borden Stevenson, late 1950s (Box 752, Folder 6)
    - Photograph - Helen Benton - May 1961 Crimea Conference - Taken by Norman Cousins - With caption, 1961 (Box 752, Folder 7)
    - Photograph - Lady Bird Johnson with painting donated by Mr. and Mrs. Benton - With correspondence, 1967 (Box 752, Folder 8)
    - Photograph - Lady Bird and Lyndon Johnson - Inscribed ephemera to William and Helen Benton, 1968 (Box 752, Folder 9)
    - 5-inch reel - "Hutchins, Stevenson, etc. Great Speech at EB Sales Dinner - Fall '59 - 2 sides - Speed 3 ¾" - With ephemera, mailing label from Encyclopedia Britannica to Mr. Charles Benton, 1959 (Box 753, Folder 1)
    - 5-inch reel - "CBS Film with Senator Benton - Per Mrs. Hoffman's memo to Senator Benton of February 13, 1969" - Handwritten note - "Send to Pheonix" and "Pheonix," 1969 (Box 753, Folder 2)
    - 7-inch reel - "From the EB - Fall of '59, Mortimer Adler on the Great Books (an unexpurgated of Hutchins, Stevenson Speech before EB salesmen)," 1959 (Box 753, Folder 3)
    - 7-inch reel - "Interview in Sen. Benton's Office on Feb. 25, 1972, The interviewer is the Rev. Don F. Crosby, S.J who has written a book about McCarthy" - "7.5 IPS" - With ephemera "To Louise Benton, Thought you might want to keep this," sender name uncertain, 1972 (Box 753, Folder 4)
    - 16mm film - Unlabelled - MGM logo visible on start of reel, undated (Box 754)
    - 16mm film - Unlabelled - "JFK ASSASSINATION" visible on film in reel, undated (Box 754)
    - 16mm film - Unlabelled - Ephemera - Original canister with crossed out mailing label from NBC to Mr. Hal Levinson - Canister had sticker with "#50" affixed to it, undated (Box 755)
    - 16mm film - "Italy Builds Again - Benton" - Two copies, undated (Box 756)
    - 16mm film - "Italy Rebuilds, Senator William Benton," undated (Box 757)
    - 16mm film - "Sen. Benton - Italy Rebuilds 1950" - With ephemera, 1950. On label: "Return to Robert F. Claffey" and contained a note from 16mm Cinema Service. (Box 757)
    - 16mm film - "New Italy," undated (Box 758)
    - 16mm film - "New Italy, First Sample Print, Benton #1145," undated (Box 758)
    - 16mm film - "The Third Hundred Years" - Encyclopaedia Britannica - With ephemera, undated. On label: Wilding, A Communications Agency Specializing in Marketing and Promotion; 18 minutes; note "w/ sollo tag." Identical label underneath, but last note replaced by "w/ sikking tag." (Box 759)
    - 16mm film - "The Third Hundred Years" - Encyclopaedia Britannica, undated. On label: Wilding, Bell and Howell; Reel Size 615'; running time 16 ½ min. (Box 759)
    - 16mm film - "Senator Benton's Campaign Spots," circa 1952 (Box 760)
    - 16mm film - "Benton, Washington TV Spot, Release Print, for [3 or 4]/3/52," circa 1952 (Box 760)
    - 16mm film - "Italy Rebuilds, TV (11:30)," undated. On label: Benton (wait for cue) 7:31 (11:30 minutes). (Box 761)
    - 16mm film - "Wm. Benton Introducing Italian Films" - With post-it note, "1952 Conn. Senate Campaign," undated (Box 761)
    - 16mm film - "Fighting Senator," circa 1952 (Box 762)
    - 16mm film - "Fighting Senator, (n50) Senate Campaign," 1952 (Box 762)
    - 16mm film - "Sen. Benton: 1952 Campaign Film" - "2/16/53" written on original canister, 1952 (Box 763)
    - 16mm film - "Here's Bill Benton" - Ephemera, letter affixed to original canister dated 2/1/1984, film undated. These two films were in the same box with the letter from 1984, which asks if two films can be spliced together. It is not clear if the second film contains the first, or if these were the two films the letter asks about putting together, of if the film from 1952 is unrelated to the letter and the second film. (Box 763)
    - 16mm film - "Title: The Chicagoans - Senator Wm. Benton, For: Encyclopedia Britannica," 1961 (Box 764)
  - Subseries 6: Oversize
    - Correspondence - Harry S. Truman - William Benton appointment as Assistant Secretary of State, November 27, 1945 (Box 765, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence – William Benton to Charles Benton, 1948-1962, This correspondence includes enclosed articles and speeches by William Benton and others. One letter contains Benton's explanation of Truman's victory in 1948. (Box 765, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence - Materials sent to Charles Benton by the William Benton Campaign, 1952 (Box 765, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence - Materials sent to Marjorie Craig (Benton) from the William Benton Campaign, 1952 (Box 765, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence - Archibald MacLeish to William Benton, 1972 (Box 765, Folder 5)
    - Campaign literature and memorabilia – [Collected by Charles Benton?], 1956, Adlai Stevenson campaign memorabilia book of matches from the 1956 Democratic National Convention removed from folder. See staff. (Box 765, Folder 6)
    - Articles – Book review clippings of John Kenneth Galbraith's The New Industrial State, undated (Box 765, Folder 7)
    - Political Cartoon - Herb Block - Drawing of William Benton - "The American Story" - With inscription to William Benton, 1950 (Box 766, Folder 1)
    - Political Cartoon - Herb Block - Drawing of McCarthy censure - With inscription to William Benton, 1954 (Box 766, Folder 2)
    - Political Cartoon - Herb Block - Print - "Children of Agnes Meyer" - With inscription to William Benton 1970 (Box 766, Folder 3)
    - Political Cartoon - Reg Manning - Drawing - "Demo. Platform Builders" - With inscription to William Benton and ephemera, 1972 (Box 766, Folder 4)
    - Political Cartoon - Sid Hix - Drawing of William Benton interrupting an NARTB-TV Board Meeting - With clipping of cartoon, undated (Box 766, Folder 5)
    - Political Cartoon - Sid Hix - Print of William Benton - With inscription to William Benton, undated (Box 766, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper - The Washington Post - "History of World War II," 1945 (Box 766, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper - The Pheonix Gazette - "The Atomic Future" by Howard Blakeslee, 1946 (Box 766, Folder 8)
    - Magazine - Life for March 1, 1948 (Box 766, Folder 9)
    - Articles about William Benton, 1948-1952 (Box 766, Folder 10)
    - Newspaper Clippings – Recipes and art, 1953 (Box 766, Folder 11)
    - Newspapers - Yale News, 1953 (Box 766, Folder 12)
    - Campaign newspapers - Democratic Party - "The New America" and "Stevenson Bandwagon," 1956 (Box 766, Folder 13)
    - Campaign Memorabilia – Democratic National Convention - Scorecard with notes, 1960 (Box 766, Folder 14)
    - Poster - Broadcast Advertising - "We Pay our Respects to William Benton" - Originally framed profile with photograph, 1938 (Box 766, Folder 15)
    - Certificate - Naming William Benton a senator from Connecticut, 1949 (Box 766, Folder 16)
    - Certificate - Appointing Helen Benton to Board of Trustees – Connecticut Child Society and Treatment House, 1958 (Box 766, Folder 17)
    - Certificate - Expression of thanks from UNESCO to William Benton, 1968 (Box 766, Folder 18)
    - Certificate - Lifetime membership of Helen Benton - Fairfield Democratic Women's Club, 1970 (Box 766, Folder 19)
    - Map - William Benton property in Southport, Connecticut, undated (Box 766, Folder 20)
    - Portrait - Laura Cornell - Drawing of Helen Benton, undated (Box 766, Folder 21)
    - Newspaper - The Arizona Republic - "V.E. Day," 1945 (Box 767, Folder 1)
    - Poster - William Benton - Senate campaign, circa 1950 (Box 767, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper articles - William and Helen Benton, 1950-1952 (Box 767, Folder 3)
    - Newspapers - National elections, 1952 (Box 767, Folder 4)
    - Articles and campgain materials - National Election, 1956 (Box 767, Folder 5)
    - Newspapers - National Elections, 1956, 1960 (Box 767, Folder 6)
    - Articles and obituaries - William Benton, 1973-1975 (Box 767, Folder 7)
    - Poster - Quotation from Old Saint Paul's Church in Baltimore, MD, undated (Box 767, Folder 8)
    - Photograph – State Department William Benton Farewell Party - With signatures, 1 October 1947 (Box 768, Folder 1)
    - Poster - "Kalendar of Principal Events in the early and middle life of William Benton," for his 65th birthday - Two copies, 1 April 1965 (Box 768, Folder 2)
    - Portrait of William Benton by Ed Weiss, undated (Box Oversize Memorabilia)
    - Monogrammed attache case, William Benton, undated (Box Oversize Memorabilia)
    - Decoupage screen of letters to "Voice of America" presented to William Benton at his State Department farewill party, 1947 (Box Oversize Memorabilia)